David Trumbull Papers
Connecticut Historical Society
David Trumbull Papers.
1773 - 1823
Connecticut Historical Society
Trumbull, David
Collection consists of personal and business correspondence; receipts, bills and accounts.
1.5 linear feet (2.5 boxes)
Related Material
An index of catalog cards is available to aid access to this collection and material in other collections. Access is through writer, recipient and date. The card catalog is located in the Research Center reading room.
Microfilm copy available.
Biographical Sketch
David Trumbull was born in Lebanon, Connecticut on February 5, 1751, the third son of Jonathan Trumbull, Sr. and Faith Robinson Trumbull. He spent most of his life as a farmer in Lebanon, though he spent many of the Revolutionary War years at the War Office as his father's right-hand man.
During the war David Trumbull helped his father raise and equip troops; he handled the forwarding of supplies not only to the land and naval forces of the state, but to the entire northern army. David served as Assistant Commissary-General under his brother, Joseph Trumbull. David's wife would later receive a pension for this service.
It was during the hostilities, on December 6, 1778, that David Trumbull married Sarah Backus, daughter of Ebenezer and Eunice Dyer Backus of Norwich, Connecticut. David's brother, Jonathan, had married Sarah's sister, Eunice, in 1769. Together they had six children, one of whom died immediately after birth.
Trumbull spent the remainder of his life after the war in Lebanon, Connecticut, where he was active in local affairs and went twice to the General Assembly as Lebanon's representative. He died on January 17, 1822; his wife followed on June 2, 1846.
Scope and Content
Collection consists largely of correspondence, letters, and supporting material written in both personal and official roles. Such correspondence is arranged chronologically. Much of the correspondence is from the period of the American Revolutionary War. There are also a few folders of receipts, bills, and accounts, also mainly from the Revolutionary period. Of particular interest is a passport, or permit of ingress, issued to David Trumbull by his father Jonathan Trumbull, Sr., Governor of Connecticut. Some notable correspondents include Peter Colt, Christopher Backus, Eliphalet Dyer, William Williams, Oliver Wolcott, James Glover, Jeremiah Wadsworth, John Porter, and Joseph Otis.
Arrangement
Materials are organized into two series based largely on form.
Series I: Correspondence consists of correspondence written by and to David Trumbull, much of which relates to his activities during the American Revolution.
Series II: Receipts, Bills, and Accounts consists of receipts, bills, and accounts, much of which relates to the Revolutionary period.
Collection is arranged chronologically within in each series.
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions on access to the collection.
Accruals
The collection is open, but additional material is not expected.
Subject Headings:
Personal Names
Backus, Christopher.; Colt, Peter, 1744-1824.; Porter, John, 1757-1806.; Otis, Joseph.; Trumbull, Jonathan, 1710-1785.; Wadsworth, Jeremiah, 1743-1804.; Williams, William, 1731-1811.
Subjects
Passports.
United States History Revolution, 1775-1783 Supplies.
Genre Forms
Holographs; holographs, signed.
Contents:
- I. Correspondence
  - Permit of ingress issued by Jonathan Trumbull, Sr., in his capacity as Governor of Connecticut, to David Trumbull., 1773 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence concerning such men as John Durkee, Josiah Elliott, Roderic Laurence, Oliver Wolcott, Jeremiah Wadsworth, and Andrew Huntington., 1776-1777 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence concerning such men as William French, Jeremiah Wadsworth, Peter Colt, and Samuel Eliot., January - September 1778 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Note: Partial list of correspondents available
  - Correspondence concerning such men as Jeremiah Ripley, Peter Colt, and John Bigelow., October - December 1778 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence concerning such men as Peter Colt, Thomas Fanning, Elisha Colt, Joshua Huntington, and Solomon Southwick., January - May 1779 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Note: Transcript available
  - Correspondence concerning such men as Samuel Broome, Elisha Colt, Thomas Johnson, and Daniel Rodman., June - September 1779 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence concerning such men as George Starr, Samuel Welles, Daniel Rodman, Peter Colt, and Simeon Thomas., October - December 1779 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence concerning such men as Joseph Williams, Nehemiah Hubbard, Roger Buckly, Joseph Packwood, and Jeremiah Wadsworth., January - July 1780 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence concerning such men as Nehemiah Hubbard, Shubael Abbe, and Jeremiah Wadsworth., August - December 1780 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence concerning such men as William Bingham, John Carter, Joshua Huntington, and Jonathan Jeffery., 1781 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence concerning such men as Ralph Pomeroy, Jonathan Jeffery, Robert Morris, and Elijah House., 1782 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence concerning such individuals as Ruth Harding, Simeon Thomas, Arnold Welles, and Christopher Backus., 1783 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence concerning such men as Christopher Backus, Joshua Stanford, Simeon Thomas, William Thompson, and Jedediah Huntington., 1784-1787 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence concerning such men as Daniel Rodman, Joseph Williams, and Jedediah Huntington., 1788 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence concerning such men as Henry Champion, William Little, Joseph Bayley, and Peter Webb., 1789 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence concerning such men as Christopher Backus, Robert Chapman, Jesse Brown, Jonathan Trumbull, Jr., Jabez Huntington, and William Little., 1790 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence concerning such men as William Little, Jabez Perkins, Simeon Thomas, Elijah House, and Epaphrodites Champion., 1791 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence concerning such individuals as William Little, Simeon Thomas, Caleb Stanley, and Lynde Huntington., 1792 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence concerning such men as Peter Christopher, Benjamin Cushing, Simeon Thomas, and John Carter., 1793 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence concerning such men as Peleg Sanford, William Little, and John Porter., January - July 1794 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence concerning such men as Jonathan Winslow, Henry Huntington, James Glover, and William Little., August - December 1794 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence concerning such men as Joseph Williams, Oliver Crocker, Nathaniel Brown, Jeremy Belknap, and Daniel White., 1795 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence concerning such men as Christopher Backus, James Lanman, and Shubael Abbe., 1797-1799 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence concerning such men as Sylvester Pratt, Peter Christopher, James Glover, and Amos White., 1800-1801 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence concerning such men as Henry Huntington, Joseph Otis, James Glover, and John Porter., 1802 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence concerning such men as Henry Huntington, Asa Spalding, Elisha Hutchinson, and James Glover., 1803 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence concerning such individuals as James Glover, Joseph Trumbull, William Williams, and Jonathan Trumbull (son of David Trumbull)., 1804-1813 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence concerning such men as James Glover, Eliphalet Dyer, Ebenezer Backus, and Rufus Payne., 1773-1822 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Fragments of correspondence; clipped autographs., 1773-1822 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- II. Receipts, Bills, and Accounts
  - Receipts, bills, accounts; concerning such men as Richard Huntly, Daniel Jones, Isaac Gillet, and Jesse Brown., 1774-1779 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Receipts, bills, accounts; concerning such men as Elijah White, Samuel Gray, Elisha Colt, and Thomas Seymour., 1780 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Receipts, bills, accounts; concerning such men as Jeremiah Wadsworth, Stephen Brown, and Abel Ellis., January - May 1781 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Receipts, bills, accounts; concerning such men as Jeremiah Wadsworth, James Phillips, Jonathan Trumbull, and Simeon Thomas., June - December 1781 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Receipts, bills, accounts; concerning such men as David Allen, William Williams, Oliver Wolcott, and John Porter., 1782 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Receipts, bills, accounts; concerning such men as Simeon Thomas, Thomas Mumford, Elijah House, Abraham Bliss, and Samuel Avery., 1783-1785 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Receipts, bills, accounts; concerning such men as Andrew Tracy, Abraham Bliss, Edward Gray, Joseph Williams, and Joshua Stanford., 1786-1789 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Receipts, bills, accounts; concerning such men as John Clark, Jr., Levi Huntington, Simeon Thomas, and Aaron Bushnell., 1790-1791 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Receipts, bills, accounts; concerning such men as Joseph Williams, Joshua Perkins, and Henry Huntington., 1792-1799 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Receipts, bills, accounts; concerning such men as Sylvester Pratt, John Maxwell, and Joseph Otis., 1800-1801 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Receipts, bills, accounts; concerning such men as John Bushnell, John Parker, Samuel Bailey, and Elisha Hutchinson., 1802-1823 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Receipts, bills, accounts; concerning such men as Joseph Loomis, William Little, Solomon Littlefield, and Benjamin Green., 1774-1823 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Receipts, bills, accounts; includes a list of debts owed by David Trumbull to several other men., 1774-1823 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Receipts, bills, accounts; includes lists of debts owed by David Trumbull to several other men., 1774-1823 (Box 3, Folder 9)